# Ryan P. Back

415.770.4228 | <a href="mailto:ryanpback@gmail.com">ryanpback@gmail.com</a> | Portland, OR GitHub.com/RyanPBack | LinkedIn.com/in/RyanPBack | RyanPBack.com

= SUMMARY =

Driven, logical, and creative junior web developer with full stack experience. Approaches new technologies with undaunted enthusiasm and a commitment to writing clean, high quality code. Experience with full web development process including project planning, identifying system requirements, design/development, testing, and implementation.

HIGHLIGHTS =

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, HTML, CSS, Sass, JSON

Frameworks/Libraries: Rails, Angular2, Bootstrap, Ember, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, D3.js, jQuery

**Web Development Skills:** Unit Testing, Debugging, Quality Assurance, UX & UI, Pair Programming, Source Control, Git, Object Oriented Programming, Relational Database Systems, API Integration, AJAX

**Non-Technical Skills:** Thoughtful Communicator, Inclusive and Team-Oriented, High Level of Integrity, Agile Learner, Inquisitive and Logical, Highly Organized, Solution-Oriented, Quick Witted & Easy Going

EDUCATION =

**EPICODUS** Portland, OR

Certificate in Web and Mobile Development (Ruby/Rails Track)

October 2016 - April 2017

Courses Completed During Full-Time Program: Introduction to Programming, Ruby, JavaScript, Rails

#### PORTLAND COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Portland, OR

55 Credits Completed Toward Associate in Science; 4.0 GPA; President's List

August 2015 – August 2016

 Computer Science Courses Completed: Intro to UNIX/Linux CS140U, Exploring Computer Science CS160, Computer Science I CS161, Computer Science II CS162

SELECTED PROJECTS =

### **CODEVELOP**

### CODEVELOP-PROJECT.HEROKUAPP.COM

Codevelop is a social networking site made for developers to connect and find other developers to work on new project ideas. Features include live reloading of in-house messages, adding and receiving followers, displaying online users, adding team members, GitHub authentication with OAuth2, and user authentication.

■ Technologies/Languages Utilized: Ruby, Sinatra, AJAX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ActiveRecord

### **imPACt**

## GITHUB.COM/RYANPBACK/imPACt

imPACt is a campaign finance tracker for Federal and State elections. imPACt allows users to view which candidates ran and for what race, who won, the total donations received, and who their top 10 financial contributors were. The user can also click on a contributor and view who they donated to and the amount donated.

Technologies/Languages Utilized: Angular2, Follow the Money API, D3.js, CSS, HTML

WORK EXPERIENCE —

### **HEYDAY ORGANIC CAFE**

San Francisco, CA

Server and Food Prep

November 2014 – March 2015

- Supported catering department by inputting orders, preparing orders, and delivering to customers
- Worked with management on process improvement and inventory control

**HD SUPPLY** 

North Highlands, CA

Flooring Merchandiser

June 2014 – October 2014

**TEMPORARY/CONTRACT ROLES** 

Roseville, CA

Customer Service

2012 - 2014

SAFEWAY

Roseville, CA

Clerk for Various Departments

October 2008 - March 2012